<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ABMA</string>

    <string name="title_section1">SCHEDULE</string>
    <string name="title_section4">SPONSORS</string>
    <string name="title_section5">CONTACT</string>
    <string name="title_section2">NOTES</string>
    <string name="title_section3">2016 INFO</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="title_activity_event">ABMA</string>

    <string name="info_2016">Badges
\nPlease make sure to wear your badges throughout the conference.  These badges are your admission to the various events and programming.

\n\nBehavioral Management Fund
\nThe BMF Committee overlooks the Scholarship/Grant process by developing the criteria for the application, review of the applications, and selection of a recipient.  The committee is also responsible for the fundraising and development of the Behavior Management Fund. The proceeds a portion of the silent auction support the Behavioral Management Fund.

\n\nABMA Travel Scholarship
\nThe purpose of this scholarship is to assist an ABMA member who would otherwise be unable to secure financial support to attend the conference. The Travel Scholarship will help the award recipient by giving them the ability to present their work and it will help the organization by giving ABMA members the opportunity to hear presentations that they would not have otherwise been able to.  The Travel Scholarship supports the ABMA Core Value of "Sharing the Knowledge".The Travel Scholarship is made possible by the Behavior Management Fund (BMF) Committee.
\nThis year’s recipient is:
\n“Here and Now with Your Animal“- Techniques to Improve the Mental Awareness of Trainers and So Enable More Effective Training
\nFrantišek Šusta, Petra Jaškówová; www.trainingisdialogue.com
\nFor more Travel Scholarship information or to apply for next year’s conference, please visit www.theabma.org.

\n\nConservation Gift
\nEach year the BMF provides a conservation-related gift to conference delegates.  This year we are doing something new! There are three different conservation organizations that delegates can vote for when registering for the conference. Each vote will correlate to a dollar amount given to that organization.
\nGopher Tortoise Council
\nhttp://www.gophertortoisecouncil.org/Guardian
\nAngel Dog Rescue
\nhttp://guardianangeldogrescue.org/
\nThe Nature Conservancy-Florida Panther Land Acquisition
\nhttp://www.nature.org/ourinitiatives/regions/northamerica/unitedstates/florida/explore/save-the-florida-panther.xmlBusiness

\n\nServices
\nThere is a business center located in the hotel.

\n\nConference Survey
\nOnce again this year ABMA is being green and doing the conference surveys online.  The results of these surveys help the ABMA to make each conference successful and better suited to the members’needs.  Your responses are greatly valued and do ensure the ABMA’s future conference programming is suited to the interests of our members. The survey will be emailed to registered delegates at the closing of the conference or accessed by the following link: http://survey.constantcontact.com/survey/a07ecc74bjtil9lzqj9/startThese surveys are an important component to the assessment of the ABMA, and we thank you for your time in completing them.

\n\nSilent Auction Donations
\nSilent auction items can be dropped off at registration.  If you did not already, please send us an email with the item you are bringing and its value, please let us know when you drop the item off so that we can create a bid sheet. </string>
</resources>
